Hello, everyone, and welcome
to the office hours for CS6300.
Shin is here as
well, but he's having
minor sound issues,
and while he corrects
that, he asked me
to get us started.
So hi, everyone, and
let Paola say hi.
I can also say hi. I also
have some communication
issue, but these are
more related to my voice
than my mic, but it will
go away, and still I hope
you can hear me well.
It's much better already.
and shin how are you doing now
are you with us now sounds
like he's not hearing me
um so unfortunately i don't
know what announcements
he was planning on making
uh which does make this
very difficult um so do
we want to just uh well i
was going to say jump into
questions i don't have any
question right the only
question there is already
resolved and has already
been answered by justin so
So I have no
announcements to give you,
and we have no
questions to answer. But
hopefully some people
will be asking questions
while we sort of
vamp here for a bit.
And hopefully Shin
will be able to hear us
and talk in a bit
and then can give you
the announcements that
I didn't give you.
So what should we talk about
while we wait for questions?
I don't know, Will. do you
want um she usually asks
me some random question
and i like i am hello oh
no he's back he's here when
i was thinking he asked
me some random question
he came back i didn't do
the announcements because
i didn't know what to
announce and there are no
there was only one question
and justin already answered
it so we're waiting
for questions and so i
figured you might as well do
the announcements and
then come up with a random
question for us to fill time
okay So today we already
closed GPT-3, GPT-4 is
ongoing, and this week,
this Saturday, we opened
assignment 6, which is the
most interesting and
intellectual challenging one.
at the same time we will
also lock down at discussion
for uh during during the
during the week of a6
so today this office hour
is the one of the most
important and should be
one of the most active
office hours from students
especially asking about
a white box testing because
ASICS is all about white
box testing and yeah again
for for those who are
in in this oh which make
sure that you completely
understand white box
testing because that's all
owned unit for ASICS
otherwise during during ASICS
we will not have any public
post on it, a private
post is still allowed,
and we will not have OH
next week as well because
we are in the lockdown,
communication lockdown.
If we have office hours,
someone can sleep in
certain questions that can
help with the answer, so
we cannot let it happen
either. Can I ask you
a clarification, Jin?
Yeah. if if people ask
a a private question and
we decided something
that everybody should see
is it possible some
of those private
questions the instructor
may make public
yes we thank you for the
clarification yeah we we
actually did that in the
past um sometimes um in
the question uh in the
question itself students
say that hey it's fine
if uh instructor can make
this public but sometimes
we think it can be it
can be public but then we
also have to ask student
consent to make it
public as well so yeah it
goes both ways but yes it
is a possibility that um
certain certain question and
answer can be public during
this um lockdown mode
because i was just gonna i
was just gonna say you know
just because it's locked down
doesn't mean you shouldn't
be reading you know checking
in on it uh on on a
fairly regular basis um uh
because there may be some
posts even though there won't
be any from students necessarily
there may be some that
we make but i just want to
make sure that we hadn't
changed policy this semester
and i wasn't aware of it
before i said that so yeah
you want to check in because
if somebody asks a question
that we think is appropriate
for the whole class, a
clarification or something,
we may put it out there
rather than having to answer
it 47 times from everybody
asking the same question.
So don't just assume that
you can spend the week
not doing anything on there
at all, that there won't
be anything useful because
there probably will be.
Another thing that I would
like to remind you It
cannot be reminded here
enough that when you submit
ASIC, make sure that
the sanity check passed.
Otherwise, you will
be really set even if
everything is almost
correct, you will get zero.
Because what Gradescope
said is what you
get. So please, please,
please make sure
that everything passed
the sanity check.
Yeah. Now, I want to
correct something.
What Gradescope says
won't be what you get
in the sense that the
best you can get out
of Gradescope is 10
out of 100 for ASICS.
So that doesn't mean that
if it gives you 10 out
of 100, you're only going
to get 10. You can't
get better than 10 because
ASICS isn't grading
you. It's just doing some
sanity checks to make
sure that you haven't done
anything really wrong.
look at the output make
sure it looks like you
expect it to look uh look
at that but most importantly
look at that score
because if it gives you
a zero out of 10 you can
have everything right
and one stupid error but
if the thing told you hey
you got zero out of 10
you got to fix something
and you don't fix it you
will not get any points
you will get zero out
of the 100 final points
That's what that is
there for, is to make
sure that the simple
errors don't happen.
And if you ignore the fact
that Gradescope told you
that there was a simple
error and you don't fix it,
you will not be very
successful in asking for
partial points. It won't
happen, just so you know.
And there are
still no questions.
and you have muted
yourself so if you're
going to talk you
probably should unmute
and i was telling him
he was muted being
muted myself it's a
very good thing okay
here it is there we go i
have i have so many i have
so many uh tabs on on my
computer and because i'm
running Linux there is no
native Microsoft Teams or
any Microsoft suit for
that matter so I have to
use Chrome in that and then
the tab is I get lost in
all of other time anyway
I would like to have some
questions for Paula so
we are doing the I was
actually asking about to
ask you a question about the
number of tabs you have
opening because you said and
then you get lost in the
number of tabs and i i
have more than you can
see before you answer that
there is in fact a a question
finally the question is
so what are the primary
learning objectives of a6
um so paula um i can i
can do it yeah and you
know and i i actually
you know i want to say I,
you know, this class has
been developed by a person
whose main research focus
is testing and debugging,
actually. But I'm more of a
theoretician and I absolutely
love ASICS because ASICS is,
you know, for people like
me, that come from requirements,
formal verification,
testing is some of these
necessary, brutal things,
right? That doesn't
give you any certainty.
Actually, you know, like
the classic things that
people tell you, and I'm
pretty sure it's most
likely in your class, if
your test suite doesn't give
you any, doesn't report
any problem, it means that
your test suite is probably
not that very good,
right? Because the idea
of testing is that testing
has to find things. But
the fact that doesn't
find anything doesn't say
anything about your code.
And I think that the
goal of A6 is to make you
understand how all the
different criteria all
still are very incomplete,
right? So none of them
give you guarantees. How
they all combine to each
other. So this is, in
fact, a very complex
problem. And then in reality,
we compromise between
what we can actually do
with the resources and
the time we have and how
much we can guarantee.
So we can never guarantee
anything but how well we
do our job. So really the
goal of this assignment is
for you to understand the
different criteria, how
they relate to each other
and what it actually means
when you reach coverage in
a criteria versus another.
So it's really to check
if you understood the
meaning of this technique
that are explained in the
lesson, I mean, that are
also the one that people use.
Okay, I think that should
answer it really well.
Next question is, the IA6
is locked until March 14.
Are we supposed to come
up with a question today?
And we already answered
some of that. But in
short, yes, as we can
see in the schedule,
we have right in the schedule,
the notes saying that
this week is the last week
before any A6 or white
box testing discussion. So
if the students are still...
I think the problem,
Shin, is you made it sound
like you expected lots and
lots of questions about the
assignment itself, which
clearly they can't ask
specific questions about
the assignment because they
haven't seen it yet. The
point is going into that
assignment, especially since
there won't be an office hours
next week, if you have
specific questions about
white box testing, now would
be the time to ask them.
I will tell you when I
took this class back when
dinosaurs roamed the earth,
this was my favorite assignment
of the whole thing.
There are people who hate
it. Um, so it is kind of
polarizing. Um, I really
enjoyed it because as, as an
engineering minded person,
um, some of the things where
you're designing things,
design, there's not
necessarily a one right
answer, right? And with
design, there's, there's, you
know, you can do a good
design or a bad design in lots
of different ways whereas
with this it's pretty
definitive if you have the
right answer or the wrong
answer so that appeals to
my engineering brain but it
is also it is also a
little bit tricky and it is
also worth a lot of points
towards the final grade so
some people don't like it
for that reason just what
i really like about what you
say is that he also point
out something else you
didn't say but i think it's
what's what you say sparkle
in my mind is um all these
criteria right have a
foundation so they are not
they are not random and
they are connected and there
is you can think of them
as like stat and there are
mathematical rules that
connect one to the other and
this is why you have an
answer that is just one right
in this assignment rather
than the design one that
that you make which is also
probably the reason why I
really like this topic but
it's also something that
is important because I
like that you know all this
technique has been developed
and then and then I'm pretty
sure in this in the lesson
I know the slides very
well but I honestly have
never listened to the lessons
but they were recorded
but in majority in reality
people are just you know
doing this basic step but
from a foundational perspective
you built on it to try
to say can we do better And
what does it mean better?
Better means like, can I
cover something more? And
so what does more mean?
And sometimes when you're
thinking you're covering
something more, you're just
covering something different,
right? And so if you
think about that in terms of
the component of your codes,
then you can say, okay,
this is the set of things
I can cover if I reach a
certain coverage. And this
is the set of things I can
reach if I reach a certain
other coverage criteria.
How these two sets relate.
And this is not by chance.
If you understand
this, assignment
six will come very easily.
easily might be an
understatement I mean
but it's not it's not
that difficult this I
think it's an assignment
in which you need
to spend more time
thinking than writing
I don't know I should
disagree I also don't
have to grade it so I
think the people grading
it's the same but I
think this is the case
no I agree I think
it's it's there's
a there's a fair
amount of thinking um
but it should be easily
doable if you have,
you know, if you
understand the different
coverage levels and
the different forms
of white box testing,
you should be fine.
Still no questions.
Okay, let's do, what is that?
Time-killing
podcast with Paola.
So, Paula, I think in
previous office hour, we
were talking about
testing, right, as how much
is enough testing. I
think it was part of the
group project question, and
then we kind of reached,
we talked briefly about
formal verification.
But then I think we
haven't talked about
property testing, it's
some kind of in between.
How do you think about
that property testing like
pros and cons, and do you
think it's a stepping stone
or a way forward for
engineers who are used to
certain kind of testing,
hk testing only to think
about certain aspects to
be more abstract, more
mathematical um um and and
then a factor of the journey
so that they can go to
formal formal verification so
i'm not the biggest fan
if you want to hear my
thing because it's not as
approachable as testing as
not as reliable and complete
as formal verification
and so but as everything
right so I when I when I
teach in person any class
software engineering related
I always say we have these
classes because there
is no method that is is
good for everything right
otherwise it would be
this is the method just
apply it and the class
will be finished right And
so I am not that very
sure that per se it's a
substitution or a compromise
between the technique.
But I would think that there
might be a different kind
of situation in which is
probably a good way to go.
I don't know, like for
instance, if you want to
check that operations
compose correctly or things
like that, that could
be a good thing. It
depends on the focus of
the code you are analyzing.
But as I said, I'm
not really a big
fan because it has
an entry requirement
much higher than
regular testing.
but not the same payoff that
formal verification give you.
So I don't know.
And actually on this topic,
before you ask me, I don't
know how AI can help you
in that. I haven't read
anything, but I'll make a
point to check for some papers
and listen to them before
the next office hour. Right.
Do you think that an
engineer who starts with
the black box testing and
then white box testing
can easily move forward
to formal verification?
Or is that like it's a
totally different thing and
it doesn't have advantage
or disadvantage? or is that
that certain most engineer,
most tester or QA may
have disadvantage because
they have been thinking
from the edge, most of the
edge case so that they can
formulate the test. And
now they bring that mindset
into the testing and it
hones them back when they
have to think more about
certain invariants in formal
verification. I think
black box testing could be
more of help than white
box testing. So people that
look at the code, they
are usually like find
difficult to step back and
thinking, okay, what is the
property of this? But in
theory, black box testing
would come from the requirements
you start from, right?
Because you start before.
And so in that case,
from that moment of formal
verification, what you need
to do as a step is to try
to understand the formalism,
to now start formalizing
what you want to do.
So, you know, like I
think, and I find it very
valuable, even before, you
know, all this advancement
in AI, there is a lot of
work in usable formal methods
to support, you know, a
more, a less human effort
in that direction. It will
be only support because
I don't know if we ever,
I don't remember, I think
I did already, but, you
know, formal verification
as a problem, you know, if
we want to keep the whole
potential of what we can
write as code and every
possible property we want
to see is an undecidable
problem. So human in the
loop are needed, like human
contribution is needed.
But I think that the idea
of making formal methods
usable is the way to go.
Because now formal methods, I
think we talk
about this already,
because of their very high
entry requirements are used
just when they are needed
by some low requirements.
But I think there are
some other applications a
little behind that bar that
will still benefit from them.
So if we had like a form of
lightweight formal method
or usable approach, then
that would be fantastic.
There is another question.
There's another question
there if you want.
It says, it might be too
soon to ask, but does
ASICs cover only the
criterion discussed in
the lectures? or does
it include supplementary
material as well, such
as mutation testing?
Only topics in the
white box testing.
So mutation testing
is more like,
well, it's also
white box, right?
Because we definitely
need to have access to the
code, but it's not like
we have to understand the
code and then um write
the test case but anyway
to to answer yeah there's
uh on only topics covered
in in the lecture so i
didn't mean to interrupt
but since there was a
question i figured we might
as well actually that's
what we're here for so
yeah no we have
this conversation to
allow people to
ask more questions
We are also testing the
possibility to open a
podcast, but I don't know,
with your voice last week
and my voice this week, I
don't know if we are the
best possible host for a
podcast, but let's see.
With that, I think we're
pretty much over it.
so yeah um i think we
can um call it a night
and um good luck to to
our students uh with the
with the gp uh with with
the final deliverable
of gp and the upcoming
a6 and we will see you
um two two weeks from
now well wait actually
this so this week we this
week is the week before
uh a six next week we
have no um communication
******** the week after
we have spring break
so it's like we will be
off for two weeks and
return um on week 12
starting march third year
all right um such a
such a long gap but
uh yeah i think we
will see you there
okay um goodbye everyone
so long everyone bye
everyone good luck with
all and we'll see you
in yes i'm in and we'll
see you in two weeks
okay whatever count on listen
to that yeah two weeks okay bye